<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>League of Failures</title>
    <description>Cracking. Barnstorming. Brilliant.</description>
    <link>http://leaguefls.github.io.</link>
    <atom:link href="http://leaguefls.github.io./feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 22 - And Then There Were…Erm, 26.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It had seemed for an eternity that if I was ever going to free myself from the asphyxiating shackles of writer’s block, the motivation would have had to be a pretty darn good one. And so it has been. I’m not one to give in to sentiment but it does bring a whiff of quiet pride to see the LoF managerial numbers on the up again. Three recent additions means that the LoF now boasts a whopping 26 gaffers. About those - it’s not just a case of your average run-of-the-mill manager, quite the opposite. Vamperoh, Timgooner and Edmanager all represent significantly good additions to the overall competitiveness of the league.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a smattering of thoughts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The template is back - &lt;/strong&gt;There’s no point acting contrarian about it and feigning faux disgust. The template, motored forward by the marauding full-back foraging of Seamus Coleman, is back. While it’s composition is still uncertain, a fair few familiar faces stand out. At the back, Mertesacker stands tall alongside a gaggle of budget picks from sides battling it out in the bottom half of the table – Ward, Burner, Gabbidon and Chester to name a few. In midfield you&amp;rsquo;d struggle to find a midfield of note devoid of the likes of Eden Hazard, Mesut Ozil, Adam Lallana and Yaya Toure (casual&amp;rsquo;s delight). Up front it&amp;rsquo;s business as usual with the explosive potential of Luis Suarez flanked by the precocious Romelu Lukaku and/or Sergio Aguero. It remains to be seen how much the picture changes over the coming weeks in the face of the January wildcard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top ten hotting up -&lt;/strong&gt; While few have managed to ascend into the rarefied airs of the top ten, there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of tales about those who&amp;rsquo;ve fallen by the wayside – if only as a metric of just how tight the competition has become. Up top, the top four continue to set the bar, seamlessly interchanging positions between themselves with the cushion of a 60 point gap from the chasing pack. At 6th place, a mini-battle continues to wage on between Football Love and Bang Average with either seeking to consolidate a place within touching distance of the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everton welcome an embattled Pepe Mel-ful, Anelka quenelle-less West Brom for the final fixture of gameweek 22 this evening. On show, a glut of fantasy protagonists who most gaffers will be hoping deliver the goods to round off a decent week of points scoring. Over to you messrs Coleman and Romelu Lukaku (sans signature dreadlocks).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 17:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2014/01/20/gameweek-22-and-then-there-werewell-26/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2014/01/20/gameweek-22-and-then-there-werewell-26/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 17 - Ticking Over</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick gander at the log following the first instalment of this gameweek reveals a fair few patterns. First off, if you still have doubts over whether Luis Suarez is essential to this exercise then I best suggest you seek other softer, less mentally taxing fare. Embattled Cardiff rolled up to Anfield for the first encounter of the weekend to face a buoyant Liverpool side still buzzing off of their triumphs at the Lane a week before. Suarez, seemingly unperturbed by the collective weight of millions of armbands, set about destroying the Bluebirds rearguard with great guile and panache. Ably aided by the rampaging Raheem Sterling and Jordan Henderson, the Uruguayan notched two sublime goals and an assist to ensure a 3-1 win for the Reds, enough to take them to the summit of the log - if only until Monday when Arsenal and Chelsea square off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the mass angst experienced the week before from not doing so, it was pretty much a given that gaffers would hand Suarez the armband. While this meant that it was even par across the gamut, several managers still gained ground with other differentials. Yaya Toure, in particular, seems to have a cult following amongst the top ten. Wayne Rooney chipped in with two assists to assuage the worries of owners who had stuck with him despite great doubts beforehand about whether or not he would feature against West Ham. In between the sticks Mignolet continued to frustrate owners as he conceded yet again. Whether their inability to keep it clean at the back dents his appeal in goal remains to be seen. Up top, matters remain largely undecided with Giroud, Lambert and Lukaku still to play a part. The middle of the park sees a whole host of differentials yet to play their part with the general pattern being a smattering of Arsenal, Chelsea, Everton and Southampton midfielders. Significant as well remains the fact that plenty of gaffers elected to take points hits to furnish their transfer business this gameweek – how much of a factor that will end up being remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 09:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/12/22/gameweek-17-ticking-over/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/12/22/gameweek-17-ticking-over/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 14 – Anti-Fear</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Suddenly and shorn of all sense of practicality and timing, gameweek 14 emerges from the (still) burning embers of the weekend. To the optimist, an opportunity to right the wrongs of gameweeks past. To the eternal pessimist (read: me), yet another damp squib – a chance to forge ahead in my increasingly taxing journey into mid-table mediocrity. It hasn’t been that bad, you might argue. But it has. In order to grasp the full picture one only has to hark several moons back into gameweek 9, or easy street as I’d like to remember it. I’d just broken into the rarefied air of the top ten off the back of a relatively big points haul. Such was the bombast at the time that I had already began mooting myself to breach the top three by the next gameweek. Well, that never materialized. In one (not so unexpected) fell swoop, gameweek 10 sauntered along and utterly annihilated everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ill-effects persist to this day as is evidenced by this newfound chagrin with which I operate; a fear of failure. As such, the cold weekends of December shall be spent aiming to rediscover the jammy touch, the freeing sense of youthful abandon, or as &lt;strong&gt;Andrew Orina&lt;/strong&gt; would like, searching for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BdHK_r9RXTc&quot;&gt;anti-fear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 14:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/12/04/gameweek-14-anti-fear/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/12/04/gameweek-14-anti-fear/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 12 - Rapprochement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, not quite. Rancor, more like. In any case, the resumption of the Premier League juggernaut following an arduously long interlull meant that managers were back to their calculating best. The stage, grandly set, lived up to its immense billing with goals featuring high up on the menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst the league picture remains largely unchanged, there were some significant benefactors from the weekend’s goal scoring exploits. &lt;strong&gt;Andrew Orina&lt;/strong&gt; took advantage of an 82 point haul to climb into 13th place and more significantly, within 30 points off the top 10. A welcome turn in fortune for the fantasy doyen who had dwelt in the lower reaches for far too long this term. Up top, &lt;strong&gt;Reuben&lt;/strong&gt; continues to exact dominance - his 66 points saw him consolidate 1st place, opening up a 35 point gap on the rest of the pack. 1st place aside, the other positions on the log remain perilously uncertain as managers remain separated by the smallest of margins. Case in point – 9th through to 20th all lie within the 500-600 point range. Where’s a DGW when you need one, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few musings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renaissance men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gameweek 12 was over and above a weekend for forwards doing what they love most – banging in the goals. While Suarez and Aguero notching was hardly news, the return to goal scoring form for a few forwards whose stars had began fading would have had gaffers chirping and cursing (if you’d just sold ‘em, that is) as well. Romelu Lukaku, Olivier Giroud and Shane Long all served up the goods with their braces serving as reminders of how patience can pay off in the managerial stakes. Whilst their resurgence might be dented somewhat by the continuing returns from their more expensive counterparts (Rooney, Suarez and Aguero), what it does provide is food for thought for those on a budget looking to get in on the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;City imperious at home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Man United, Norwich and more recently, Tottenham, found out, Man City at the Etihad are a different kettle of fish. Having notched seven without reply past Norwich earlier in the month, City took all of 15 seconds to breach a mean Spurs defense that had conceded only 6 league goals all season. What sets City apart from most is their ability to turn the screw and exact dominance over their opponent when winning. And that’s just what they did – helping themselves to a 6-0 victory over a clueless, hapless Tottenham outfit. With a few of their fellow title hopefuls rolling up to the Etihad over the next month, it remains to be seen whether they can maintain their swashbuckling home fettle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 09:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/11/27/gameweek-12-rapprochement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/11/27/gameweek-12-rapprochement/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 11 - As We Stand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sands of gameweek 11 are definitively settled and with the interlull arriving, managers are afforded an opportunity to look back and analyse their progress (or lack of) over the last eleven weeks. Often met with palpable scorn and fervent disdain, the interlull is this time warmly welcomed apropos perhaps to the current state of the league.** **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reuben Lagat &lt;/strong&gt;continues to hold fort up top despite having a shocker last weekend - a curt reminder of the ebb and flow nature of fantasy fortunes. In what has been perhaps the most significant move (positively, at least) since the opening gameweek, &lt;strong&gt;Douglas Odipo&lt;/strong&gt; pipped &lt;strong&gt;Onesmus Nderitu &lt;/strong&gt;into &lt;strong&gt;2nd&lt;/strong&gt; place. This promises to be an interesting battle given that Reu&amp;rsquo;s poor return means the gap between the top three has now been greatly reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Chichop &lt;/strong&gt;continued to add weight to his maverick status, this time posting a league high 89 points to drive him into &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt;. Up next remain the ever-presents. 5th to 9th place have largely featured the same faces since the start of the campaign. Of these it is Allan Omoga&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Mystagogue FC &lt;/strong&gt;and Fabian Ntabo&amp;#39;s &lt;strong&gt;Die Mannschaft &lt;/strong&gt;who have exhibited probably the greatest constistency. **
**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further afield and two great rivals adorn subsequent positions on the log. &lt;strong&gt;Saddam Sadd&lt;/strong&gt;, of the كرة القدم الحب persuasion, struggling to rediscover his sizzling early season form and Freedom of Tchoyis&amp;#39; &lt;strong&gt;Dennis Kigen,&lt;/strong&gt; stuck in a first gear after a spate of good form saw him climb to as far as 7th place. Just below is Sammy Goin&amp;rsquo;s indifferent &lt;strong&gt;BombarderFC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, fate conspires to have the league&amp;rsquo;s ladies within touching distance of each other.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;13th&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sheila Minayo &lt;/strong&gt;travails persist as she seeks to make up ground on a leading pack within which she featured not so long ago. In 14th, &lt;strong&gt;Cindikate FC&amp;#39;s &lt;/strong&gt;Cindy Oronga experiences much the same. Having had to contend with very tetchy recent form, she now has to consider the impending challenge posed by the two managers below her on the log - &lt;strong&gt;Dennis Korir&lt;/strong&gt; and&lt;strong&gt; Hillary Egesa&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 17th placed &lt;strong&gt;Andrew Orina&lt;/strong&gt;, January cannot come soon enough. Recently touted to be on the path to redemption, his efforts at recovery fizzled out no sooner had they began to take shape. Now seemingly rooted to the fantasy nadirs, last season&amp;rsquo;s champion faces a huge battle to ensure that this campaign is not consigned to the throes of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s that for now then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 12:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/11/13/gameweek-11-digest-as-we-stand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/11/13/gameweek-11-digest-as-we-stand/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 10 - Abberation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a pain that only the most seasoned of fantasy football campaigners would resonate with enough to comprehend. The narrative is a well told one across the fantasy fold - riding high off of the fervent buzz of a winning game week only to be utterly and completely annihilated by the sickening crash of failure. Looking back on the events immediately preceding this aberration, I struggle to envisage a different outcome. I had set myself up for failure really by failing to act. The decision to casually ignore Sergio Aguero’s effervescent form looms large in the memory, as does the faux confidence borne off of handing Romelu Lukaku the armband.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distant feeling of angst that I had &lt;a href=&quot;http://leaguefls.wordpress.com/2013/10/27/gameweek-9-catharsis/&quot;&gt;predicted&lt;/a&gt; (eerily) now prevails as I stare back at the computer monitor. The output, unchanging, stares back taciturnly. 37 measly points gleaned, I chuckle. That’s nearly the same tally Aguero managed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB: It would probably serve me better to churn out an abridged version here, if only to gloss over my (and others) managerial blushes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up top, &lt;strong&gt;Reuben Lagat&lt;/strong&gt; continued to exact his superiority, this time his impressive efforts resulting in a substantial widening of the gap between him and chaser &lt;strong&gt;Onesmus&lt;/strong&gt;. His 91 point haul, streets ahead of all and sundry, only just another feather in a steadily growing cap. An unabating spate of consistently fine form which he attributes, rather interestingly, to a recent conversion to Buddhism. Make of it what you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down to 2nd place Onesmus managed 40 points, only just enough to keep Douglas Odipo’s &lt;strong&gt;Excelsia FC&lt;/strong&gt; at bay. While &lt;strong&gt;Fabian Ntabo’s&lt;/strong&gt; 44 points were not especially spectacular, they facilitated a rise in position above &lt;strong&gt;Allan Omoga&lt;/strong&gt; (who got 41). Kevin Adhaya of &lt;strong&gt;Bazinga FC&lt;/strong&gt; rose above &lt;strong&gt;Saddam Sadd&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;yours truly&lt;/strong&gt;, both for whom the less said the better. Further afield, &lt;strong&gt;Andrew Orina&lt;/strong&gt; set sail to his revival campaign, helping himself to a healthy 60 points and a rise into 14th place. Other risers were &lt;strong&gt;Lost Lawz’s&lt;/strong&gt; Hillary Egesa and &lt;strong&gt;Allan Kisanya&lt;/strong&gt; of Royal Pains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stage is set then for gameweek 11 as the League of Failures begins to take shape. The events of the gameweek past will no doubt alter the reckoning of most as the jousting for positions intensifies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bid fair welcome (as is the norm) to our newest entrant, Robert Chelule and his &lt;strong&gt;Didge FC&lt;/strong&gt; outfit, fresh-faced and unaware of the trials and tribulations that await him. This, my friend, is fantasy football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrivederci,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 11:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/11/09/gameweek-10-abberation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/11/09/gameweek-10-abberation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 9 – Catharsis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Afternoon LoFers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s slightly over noon as I emerge from the covers, still buoyant and resplendent with the afterglow of fantasy success. As the points total attest, the last two gameweeks (this one most certainly included) have been something of a managerial catharsis, and a timely one at that. The events of gameweek 7 still linger in the psyche, the ignominy of which most are still smarting from. The turbulent wave now appears rode and the fixture list affords decent opportunity for building a head of steam. Nevertheless, as a head as experienced in the sheer unpredictability of fantasy football as my own would know, angst is never far off; more so in the face of such unfettered glee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst the sands from the gameweek remain far from settled, the LoF picture has seen a raft of movement. The jousting at the very zenith that has characterized the season so far showed no signs of letting up. Last night it was Onesmus Nderitu with the definitive jab, elevating himself to just the point above Herr Reuben. &lt;strong&gt;Excelsia FC’s&lt;/strong&gt; 43 points kept him within sight of the front two as his consistent efforts continue to prevent the gap from them furthering. Under the aegis of a rampaging Luis Suarez and with maximum points gleaned from defense, Allan Anyona’s &lt;strong&gt;Mystagogue FC&lt;/strong&gt; delivered a sensational 73 point haul. A devastating return as Peter Bahati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Bison Herd&lt;/strong&gt; realized, his team effectively consigned to 6th as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However much the gameweek remains to change, great praise must be lauded to the efforts of Dennis Kigen’s &lt;strong&gt;Freedom of Tchoyis&lt;/strong&gt;. While his 60 point haul was not especially spectacular (given what transpired elsewhere), the context in which it arrives offers far greater perspective. Currently 7th, the fact that Dennis has played a gameweek less than everyone else in the top 16 provides a decent metric of the kind of form the fantasy stalwart has been in. What it also reveals is exactly how terribly most LoF managers have fared this term – of notable mention here being the likes of Eric Njagi, Robert Okello and Andrew Orina. It remains to be seen how he saunters on from here on, not least after this gameweek, but what’s certain is that his ascension into the top 10 has set a marker to the rest of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty remains to be decided as 4 fixtures are still to be played out. The Tyne-Wear derby sees Newcastle trot up to the Stadium of Light to face Gus Poyet’s Sunderland. The highlight of the day no doubt sees Chelsea squaring up against City with the race for the title firmly on the menu. Tottenham accost Hull City and Swansea await the visit of the Hammers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about the size of it then,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addendum&lt;/strong&gt;: Here&amp;rsquo;s something I did and thought you might fancy. Word clouds and all that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://leaguefls.files.wordpress.com/2013/10/wordcloud.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://leaguefls.files.wordpress.com/2013/10/wordcloud.png?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;word cloud&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See if you can spot yourself in there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 10:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/10/27/gameweek-9-catharsis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/10/27/gameweek-9-catharsis/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 8 - Partial Retribution</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The gloves were off for Saturday as managers readied themselves yet again for a dabble at the fantasy juggernaut. The managerial palate was sufficiently sated and breath bated at the prospect of some tantalising weekend clashes. At stake, the potential for points on the board as well as the ever-looming feeling of angst (both being dished in increasingly equal measure these days). To this effect, the weekend did not disappoint as with it came a barrage of points, talking points and all round good football. Notable amongst a plethora of gleanable subplots remains the unabating form of Aaron Ramsey. Not only has the rampaging Welshman been banging in the goals for Arsenal but he has also continued dishing out retributive justice to those who have given him the cold shoulder. Incredible still is that even despite multiple price rises, the midfielder continues to present tremendous value at a mere £6.8m for those on the managerial throes keen on joining the party, even at this late juncture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ramifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The League of Failures remains largely unchanged save for a dribbling of movement at the top half. Up top, the impressive Reu pipped Onesmus into 1st place, his 65 point haul fashioning a 10 point gap over his nemesis. Die Mannschaft and FC Sirius Black both moved up a notch into 8th and 9th respectively, this at the expense of Cindikate FC and Bazinga FC. Further afield, Dennis Kigen’s Freedom of Tchoyis skedaddled into 12th courtesy of his 64 points. Sheila Minayo’s 41 points could only see her consigned to a drop into 13th. Last week’s marquee mover Joel Drake struggled to replicate that form, dropping into 15th. The picture shall not doubt change come Monday evening given that two fixtures are still yet to be played. Today sees Villa welcoming an indifferent Tottenham, with the likes of Benteke, Soldado and Eriksen expected to play significant roles. Monday sees Fulham make the short trip to Selhurst Park to face Crystal Palace in a match more notable for the fates of the two gaffers than anything else. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sizzling Arsenal&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the aegis of the mesmerizing talents of the mercurial Mesut Özil, Arsenal’s fettle isn’t looking anywhere near burning out. Top of the log and maintaining consistent membership in amongst the goals and assist charts, the Gunners have continued to exhibit championship-winning form all the while presenting a wide array of assets for the fantasy reckoning. With Palace rolling up in the weekend, it is expected that Arsenal assets will continue to enjoy great interest in the fantasy stakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Southampton cannot be ignored&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hot of earning a great point at Old Trafford, the Saints have continued to show good value for their 4th place standing on the log. Mean in defence, Robin van Persie’s effort was only the first time their backline had been breached in five gameweeks. Adam Lallana and Dejan Lovren remain standout options at either end of the pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s that for now then, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Edit: Post incomplete as I’m off to the football. Editorial privileges and all that&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Addendum: Ended up scoring just the five goals at the football today, Sunday League Ronaldinho and all that…]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 12:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/10/20/gameweek-8-partial-retribution/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/10/20/gameweek-8-partial-retribution/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 6 - Jangling Nerves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Afternoon folks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gameweek 6 beckons, and with it the inevitable jangling of managerial nerves as gaffers look to tune and tinker their elevens. Injuries to key players continues to be the overriding theme with a whole host of fantasy stalwarts having to contend with periods on the sidelines. Upfront, doubts still linger over Robin van Persie’s availability for United’s clash against West Brom with the Dutchman looking to shake off a groin strain. In midfield, Aaron Ramsey is expected to recover from a thigh niggle in time for Arsenal’s journey to Swansea. Theo Walcott remains sidelined for “realistically five weeks” according to his manager while Mathieu Flamini set to shake off a small shoulder complaint. There is also concern over the availability of Hull City’s Robbie Brady following doubts indicating that the popular midfield pick might require surgery to resolve a hernia problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suarez returns&lt;/strong&gt;
With the Uruguayan having served a 10 match ban, Luis Suarez returns to the Liverpool fold for the match against Sunderland. Having got 90 minutes of action under his belt in midweek, Suarez walks straight back into a Liverpool side suffering injuries to key players. Coming in at £10.9m, he offers a different proposition to managers looking to seal holes left by the likes of &lt;strong&gt;Christian Benteke&lt;/strong&gt; and possibly &lt;strong&gt;Robin van Persie&lt;/strong&gt;. Injury to creative cog Philippe Coutinho means that Suarez will likely slot in just behind the in-form &lt;strong&gt;Daniel Sturridge&lt;/strong&gt; with the pair expected to rekindle the fruitful partnership they showed last season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lukaku in the reckoning&lt;/strong&gt;
With several of the mid-price forward brigade faltering this season, the emergence of Romelu Lukaku could just be the tonic managers have been seeking thus far. Impacting immediately with a goal as a second half substitute against West Ham, the hirsute Belgian afforded managers a brief reminder of his capabilities. Despite facing competition from the likes of Nikica Jelavic and Arouna Kone, Lukaku’s form makes him an automatic pick for Everton’s Monday showdown against Newcastle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michu looms&lt;/strong&gt;
Despite having struggled in the earlier weeks of the season, Michu looks to have rekindled the sort of form that made him a devastating prospect last season. A run of three goals in three games coupled with a kind fixture list (beyond this weekend’s visit of Arsenal, anyway) sets the Spaniard high on the list of midfield offerings alongside the likes of &lt;strong&gt;Mesut Özil&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Aaron Ramsey&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Christian Eriksen&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addendum&lt;/strong&gt; 
The Fantasy Football Scout &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fantasyfootballscout.co.uk/2013/09/27/scout-picks-gameweek-6-2/&quot;&gt;scout picks&lt;/a&gt; for Gameweek 6 are out. The unavailability of Sergio Aguero, Theo Walcott, Christian Benteke and potentially Robin van Persie ultimately decides matters as the Scout attempts to seek out able replacements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boruc 
    Baines - Vidic - Kompany - Wilson
             Michu - Özil - Moses
       Lambert - Rooney - Negredo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backup brigade: &lt;strong&gt;Riether, Arnautovic, Lukaku&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 11:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/09/27/gameweek-6-jangling-nerves/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/09/27/gameweek-6-jangling-nerves/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gameweek 5 - Schrödinger's Cat</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Evening folks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The events of the gameweek gone by linger freshly in the memory as managers try to collate and make sense of the attendant babble. The League of Failures picture is sufficiently muddied, with tables turned over their heads, sporadic success stories and an ever-growing underbelly of angst. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MOVEMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Douglas Odipo dug up a barnstorming 82 points to propel him straight up to 3rd place on the log. Onesmus and Reuben meanwhile did enough to maintain parity in the top two slots. Mystagogue and Bazinga FC saw drops in positions as did Benson Musa, who fell the most down into the 8th. Subsequently, Fabian&amp;rsquo;s aptly named Die Mannschaft quietly stole into 5th with a 62 point haul. Close on his heels was Alex Baraka who moved to 6th. Cindy Atieno drew 57 points to move on up to 9th. Further afield, Sheila Minayo saw a further drop into the mire, managing only a meagre 22 point return. Robert Okello&amp;rsquo;s schocker trundled on, this time his 28 point return consigning him to 18th. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few musings&amp;hellip; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early shockers showing no signs of abating&lt;/strong&gt;
Just when we thought no one could best Andrew Orina&amp;rsquo;s total mare of season, Robert Okello has gone one better, registering a most spectacular implosion in the last few weeks. Comfortably amidst the top 3 only 3 weeks ago, his ailing side now lies 18th. This is following an inexplicable 44 point hit over the weekend after making 12 transfers and &amp;lsquo;forgetting&amp;rsquo; to employ his wildcard. Tough times. Elsewhere, Andrew Orina&amp;rsquo;s 43 point haul, while decent enough to see him maintain his position, will be scant consolation for the seasoned campaigner. Following his spectular exploits last season, many had mooted him to be there and thereabout this campaign. And with good reason. His domineering managerial savvy had seen him lead the last campaign from start to finish. Having been expected to replicate the same, Orina has struggled woefully. Rooted to the wrong half of the table, he has had to contend with being overtaken by the likes of Joel Drake and Dennis Kigen despite both having played a gameweek fewer. Drastic times indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bensoo&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;treads slippery slope&lt;/strong&gt;
A permanent fixture at the top from the start of the season, Ben&amp;rsquo;s most recent effort saw him muster a meagre 28 point haul. While not so poor a return given what others around him managed, the result was poor enough to see him resigned to 8th place. No stranger to cutting off the nose to spite the face, Ben&amp;rsquo;s recent travails have been the epitome of knee-jerk. Despite deciding early doors to eschew including van Persie in his side, a tasty fixture against Crystal Palace saw Ben fall over himself to shuffle his team in order to get the mercurial Dutchman. A decision which ultimately proved far from handsome as not so soon after he had had to employ his wildcard to reorganise his side once more following the botched RvP transfer. Now sporting an entirely new side as well as an unconventional 5-2-3 formation, it remains to be seen whether Ben will be able to turn things round and get back to winning fettle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reuben a model of consistency&lt;/strong&gt;
Perhaps wrongly tipped to struggle at the start of the term (on account of his relative lack of experience), Reuben&amp;rsquo;s early form has gone a lot farther than silencing the doubters. With a scorecard reading 70, 54, 66, 65 and more recently, the LoF new boy is showing the sort of form many had thought to be the sole preserve of seasoned campaigners. Firmly settled at 2nd and with Onesmus well in his sights, it remains to be seen how he fares throughout the rest of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about the size of it then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 17:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/09/24/gameweek-5-schroedingers-cat-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leaguefls.github.io./2013/09/24/gameweek-5-schroedingers-cat-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>